[Music]
hello and welcome everyone to this
business Central launch event for 2025
release wave 1 in this segment I would
like to tell you about a very very
interesting capability that we built in
business Central called sales order
agent it is in fact the very first agent
born in business Central helping the
sales team manage their operations with
capturing quotes and converting these
quotes into sales orders so you can
imagine that any random sales team
spending a lot of time scanning through
the emails coming into their mailbox
trying to understand whether this email
is even relevant uh sales request or not
and having understood that yes it is in
fact a quote request they would
typically go into business Central and
start performing many interesting
activities inside of the product trying
to see whether they have the in ventory
uh in place whether this is the right
customer uh how to how and when the
customer wishes to deliver uh the items
all of these questions require time for
salese doing these activities inside of
business
Central so with the sales order agent
approach we Chang in this space to 100%
automate this entire process end to end
and yet keep the sales team in the loop
so so that instead of humans and sales
operators clicking around the product
and trying to address the request for
the quote it is an agent which is now
helping the sales team do all of these
things just from an email that they
receive from the customer and instead of
me just talking a lot about it let me
show all of this through the product so
here we are in business Central
beautiful interface and the very first
thing which I see and I may be biased in
this particular situation is the
salesorder agent tile in the upper right
corner so this is where our agents the
salort agent and many agents uh in the
future will have their home and will
have their presence it is staying there
invisibly until activated so that's
exactly what I'm going to do if I'm just
going to hover over this uh Avatar of
the cells or agent you see here's the
the first uh p P that's uh that I can
observe as an administrator setting up
the sales or agent and we build it in a
way that it's very easy to activate so
one action throws into into my face when
I as I look at it is activate action so
here's the configuration dialogue for
the sales or agent and right now it only
has very very few options so in fact if
I scroll to the right you see that's as
much set up as you would need to do to
make this feature work there's a couple
of options for the administrators to
configure uh the experience of the agent
uh in different
situations but generally what you need
to do to get started is to define a
mailbox account so let me go ahead and
do that I will click on these three dots
and then go through the setup wizard by
the way uh please use Microsoft 365
account uh for the sales or agent and it
has to be a shared mailbox uh which you
can figure for this purpose
I'm going to click next and I'm going to
give a name to my uh email account that
the agent is going to monitor for the
incoming mail requests from customers so
for example this one is going to be
called Kronos
sales and here's the email account which
I configured so I'm going to click next
this is all standard set up for
configuration of emails and business
Central there's nothing new in this
particular setup experience
so I'm just going to pick that account
that I have just configured hit okay and
now the email box is configured and the
agent is running and all I need to do is
hit update and the agent will now
monitor that mailbox but before I do
that I wanted to show another place on
this experience you see the sales order
agent is meant to help the sales team
process these quote requests and here on
this experience I I can add additional
users to the agent and then these users
which I add uh will be able to interact
with the agent the users will be able to
review the tasks uh processed by the
agent uh reconfigure the agent if
necessary and delegate tasks to it so
this is where you can figure it uh in
this environment I'm all by myself very
very sad but in your sales team I'm
pretty sure there will be many people
into interacting with the cells or agent
okay so all I need to do is just hit
update and the agent gets activated so
now you see the tile has changed and it
no longer has the pose button on it and
let's me just hover over and that's the
first time you see the kpis the agent
kpis being activated and obviously they
all zeros at this point of time so the
agent hasn't done any job no praise yet
uh for the agent but let's let's see how
it interacts with the very first
requests for that I can navigate to the
task
pane otherwise this task pane as you can
see resides in the co-pilot pane so the
co-pilot is the view uh for the users
into the world of Agents so this is
where you will see the tasks coming in
from the mailbox and the agent will
start processing these tasks so by the
way here's the easy shortcut to the um
to the configuration experience if you
need to go back and uh configure the
agent uh add a few more configuration
options all right so at this point of
time it's configured there's nothing
else I need to do but let's now step
into the shoes of the customer of this
company sending a request for a
quote so for that I will navigate into
the mailbox of the customer and here I
have prepared a few emails for us to uh
to play with and understand the
capabilities of the agent
so for example let me uh go ahead and
send this email and while it is being
delivered uh I can step back into
business Central now technically right
now what's happening in the background
there is a business logic inside of
business centrol which checks that
mailbox periodically uh whether there's
new emails uh available for for the
agent to pick up and as soon as it
discovers that yes there is a new email
you see it is picking up the task and
starting to process it so right now it
fetches it from the from Outlook it
tries to read the text it tries to
understand what the text is about and it
tries to see whether it's a relevant
request whether it's a request it wants
to proceed with or not so let's let's
give it a few seconds to uh to
complete all right in this particular
case we were looking straight at the
screen for maybe a few seconds given
time to the agent to process that email
in the real life though though you don't
have to look at uh at this pain all the
time so you can you can just close it
and go your uh way in business Central
do your job and do your tasks and the
agent will call out to you when it
requires your attention so in this case
let's take a look at what's uh what's
the agent received so here's a request
from Yan and in this experience I can
preview the email received by the agent
so you you see I'm I'm here clicking
drilling through into the step I can see
the email message I can see when it is
received who it is received from but the
contact the person who sent this email
is an unknown contact now it's important
to mention that the sales or agent only
works with registered contacts and
customers inside of business Central at
least at this point of time who knows
what the future will the future will
bring however we made it convenient for
you to just in time create and register
that contact in business Central and
proceed with the flow here you also see
hey there's there's a nice notification
thrown to you uh that the contact with
this email is not
found good so now we can we can look
through the text of the email uh just
like you would in Outlook however you're
just reviewing it here in in BC and
let's see what exactly this customer is
asking for so they're not just asking
for specific furniture they asking for
this furniture made of specific material
uh for example hey I would like it to be
in cotton and I would like it to be of a
very specific color so this request may
come in many different shapes and forms
and the agent should be able to search
through through this information very
very reliably so I'm going to kick off
the agents to uh to proceed with its
task but in the meantime let me explain
a few words about the search so what the
agent can do it can search through the
inventory in business Central and it Ed
many many parameters and surrounding
data of the items to find the correct
ones so one obvious example would be
using the just the title uh of of a of
an item but the agent goes beyond that
so it uses search uh to not only read
through the data on the item table or
card itself it also goes into to the
related information it can it can search
through extended texts it can search
through translations it can search
through item
attributes so it will search through all
and by the way item categories as well
and category codes so it searches
through multiple tables to understand if
this is the right item that the the user
is asking for or not so let's take a
look and review this information here's
something that the agent has already uh
performed the search on
and it comes back with the results look
these are the ones that we uh we have in
our stock so these are the the chairs
which match your request and it adds a
few more Dimensions to this reply so
here's the items with a certain
availability level so the users can see
whether the items are available or not
uh we also show the pricing point and
the using unit of
measure so how does the agent check for
availability
now this is an interesting uh experience
that you may want to to to try and play
with so the agent uses a page called
item availability
page which human users and human
operators can definitely use as well so
to understand whether items are
available or not and we specifically
designed this page to be very helpful to
the agent so you can go ahead and apply
certain filters for example I'm I'm
searching for chairs so these are these
are my chairs and I'm searching on a
specific date filter and I'm searching
for a specific customer and I'm
searching for a specific location and
this is the quantity that I'm looking
for so for example 20 um the quantity of
20 of a specific item and here on this
page we're listing some of the key
parameters that you as a salesp person
would want to have having the
conversation with the customer and we
combining these data points here here on
this page uh the the unit price the
discount uh all linked to these filters
to calculate the
availability and here you see a very
simple flag whether the items following
this configuration are available or
not so this is this is the information
that we are wrapping with the response
of the agent here and uh the the human
uh operator can review this outgoing
email message um so it appears to be
working fine and and they can confirm to
proceed so I'm confirming this message
and off it goes to Yan explaining which
items are available or not imagine this
situation done before the agent uh was
introduced in business Central you would
probably have to do quite a few steps to
understand which items have been
requested which items have been
available not available and things of
that
nature so now look let's look at another
scenario here's another task which uh
the agent just processed this time it's
an email coming from Helen so let's see
what was done by the agent in this case
I as an human operator I can still
review what was requested and in this
case Helen is asking for the very very
long list of chairs again it would
probably have taken me a long long time
to understand uh whether we have these
items available what are the prices what
are the terms and conditions Helen is
also asking for a specific delivery date
so she she wants the items to be
delivered early next month uh she wants
to register her own purchased document
number uh just to make it easier for her
to find it in in her system so there's
there's a lot going on in this email but
the great thing about it is that I don't
have to read this email the agent has
already read this email and it did
create a sales quote automatically and
it updated that quote with uh details
requested by Helen so the details are
mentioned here uh in the user experience
so can click on these fields and see
exactly how these fields are
populated and if you notice as well all
of these items requested by Helen so
they are added here to the sales quote
with all of the requested quantities and
all of the data pulled by the system so
instead of creating this document
manually the agent helped prepopulate
and pre-create that quote so everything
I need to do is generally review this
outgoing email request so all of the
quantities and items uh look good um and
um I'm just going to confirm and send it
to
Helen so this is the process of agent
helping the sales team processes process
these requests and it can support
scanning the inbound emails it can
support checking the items
availability uh it can also work uh on
creating the actual sales quote
iterating on the sales quote if Helen
comes back and wants to change one or
two lines uh on this sales quote the
agent will find that quote and update
the line and finally when Helen confirms
that email message uh it will be
converted from quote into an order a
curious to see how it looks like from
the customer perspective let me show you
that
part so let me navigate back into into
the Inbox and show you how it looks like
from the customer perspective so here's
a conversation between Yen and the sales
order
agents conversing very naturally in
natural language with Yen asking some
questions hello uh do you have such and
such items in your inventory the sales
order agent is replying with all of the
things that we've seen through the demo
then Yan is uh making his choice of
specific items having seen all of these
inventory so he's asking for two Tokyo
cheers uh the sales order agent prepares
and sends the sales quote so I can open
the attachment and and see it comes
directly from business Central looks
good and then what happens next is Yan
says that's good so let's proceed with
the order and that quote is converted to
a sales order so now the sales order
confirmation is received the order is
captured uh Ian is happy because all of
it has happened in the matter of uh some
minutes rather than maybe days
in worst case so this is the
conversation seen from the customer
eyes all right
but sometimes the agent does receive
much more interesting uh emails so let
me show you that example as
well so let's look at this couple of
emails in the first case uh let me just
go ahead and click and open it you see
that the agent tagged this inbound email
with a warning text so it actually says
that hey this incoming message appears
not to be relevant to sales or agent so
in fact I can just ignore this message
stop the task and leave it there but I'm
curious to see what it is so let me open
it up and of course it's one of those
tacky commercials that you sometimes get
in your outlook mailbox once in a
lifetime
opportunity 100% legit no risk you can
make $10,000 every week wouldn't you all
love to receive such emails in your
mailbox you probably would but it's not
something business critical and
therefore the agent is telling you hey
this message is a promotional
advertisement not related to what sales
agent should be doing however if you
choose to proceed you can because there
there may be some cases where it's not
so obvious that this is uh some
promotional campaign but you can ask the
agent to give it a
try however there may be another
situation where the the message is
harmful so the message contains some
content which can be disturbing and
cannot be you know just taken lightly in
this case you can see that we're making
an effort of even hiding this message so
the the content of the message is
blocked and um not made visible to the
user the user can still open it up and
review uh I'm not going to do that right
now but generally the system will not
allow
to for these messages to proceed in the
system in uh in processing so if you
could say that hey agent even though
it's not relevant give it a try for the
messages which are obviously harmful uh
the agent will not allow processing such
messages so that's another way uh that
for for the agent to save time for you
and not waste it on processing some
advertisement or openly harmful
emails one other thing which I want to
to to show you is that after having
worked with the agent for some time
imagine that it it did help processing
so many emails for your team and
generally as you have seen me doing in
this demo all the salese need to do is
review the information generated by the
agent and approve or decline the
messages so that is that is the type of
work that they would be doing reviewing
the agent activities and all of the time
saved can be used on much more
fulfilling activities of actually
calling the customers making the deals
agreeing on some final details and
polishing these orders before they they
fulfilled so there's just so much time
spent uh on these activities and you
might be asking how much time is spent
on these activities and for that we
built this kpis dialogue which is right
now already filled up with some data so
we did receive several emails so you
saved Time by not reading these emails
you save time by not creating the
document manually and some of the quotes
were converted into the orders so this
dialogue would give you just a hint of
insight of what kind of effort the agent
is saving you so you can spend that
effort uh on some other
tasks now one final piece of uh
information which I wanted to share with
you is just a little bit of insight into
how the agent
works under the hood I'm not going to go
into deep technical details but
generally if you think about it the
agent has access to the entirety of
business Central application and it
accesses business Central through the
user interface it is not analyzing
pixels and dots on the screen it
actually can connect to the actions
controls uh
data displayed on the UI to understand
how perform the task to understand which
steps to take and how to complete the
given
assignment now it has access to all of
the richness of the metadata the names
of the actions uh the names the captions
of these actions uh all of it is fed
into the uh into the engine of the agent
behind the scenes and it reasons over
these data and decides how to fulfill
this this task and how to go about uh
completing that assignment and you might
think that hey this is very overwhelming
because business Central has a lot of
functionality I mean look at it let me
just open this uh this view I love
seeing it every time I look at it
there's just so much capabilities built
into business Central Erp application
but we want to somehow limit what the
agent can do and see so let me show you
that if I go into the agent card you
will notice that agents are designed
based on the same Principle as the users
so if I open the agent card it looks
very very similar if not 100% the same
to the layout of the user card so here
you see the the general information
about the agent the name and the
description and display name here you
see agent permission sets so this is the
first level of control that
administrators can use to provide
limited scope of authorization to this
agent so through these permissions which
by the way come with the agent agent
itself built by Microsoft so we did
outline the exact permissions needed for
the agent to fulfill its task in this
permission sets so I can look it up and
then see what is included with these
permission sets so I can just scroll all
the way down see what kind of tables and
capabilities the agent has access to uh
if I disable this agent so I need to
disable this agent to be able to to
modify these permissions I can go and
modify them adjust uh make it more
strict or make it you know more uh
flexible so up to you as an
administrator because no business
Central is the same you probably need to
a little bit tune these permissions uh
you will also see some of the users
which all of the users which were given
access to the agent but one other
interesting thing is that you will also
see the profile used by the
agent now instead of me explaining so
what the profile does to the agent let
me just go ahead and change the profile
so as I would do for a typical user I
would go into my settings and here I
will find this sales order agent
co-pilot profile and let me switch that
apply it to
myself and it will reload the business
Central and let's see what happens on
the
screen so now if I go back to the Roll
center we're looking at the business
Central capabilities Through The Eyes of
the agent so you see that this user
experience is much lighter it has
nothing which the sales or agent is not
supposed to work with it has access to
the list of it can see it can interact
with the list of customers contacts
sales quotes and sales orders and under
the sales menu it can only go into the
sales quotes we also refined what you
can see on the sales quote card itself
you see there's no fact boxes there's no
irrelevant information we cleaned up
this form to remove uh the things which
are not 100% relevant to the role of the
agent so this form is much lighter and
it's made so through their changes to
the
profile so using profiles you can design
the interaction surface of the agent and
expose or hide certain controls from
from its view this is a very powerful
model and when you think about
customizations that you may have in your
system you you will you may definitely
have a few extra fields or a few extra
actions or maybe many actions and Fields
available on the sales quote and sales
order by adding these fields and actions
to the sales order agent profile you
make them available for the agent to
interact with so the agent can discover
these fields and try to set them up and
configure and reconfigure this
particular sales quote so that's a short
Glimpse under the surface to see how
administrators can control this
experience they can do it in two ways by
the uh by setting up permissions and by
setting up the profiles that was the
story of the sales order agent there's
plenty of great documentation available
for you to to study and we're really
hoping that this is the beginning of a
an amazing journey of many many agents
helping you helping your customers and
users be better at uh working with the
product working with their clients
working with their customers and
generally enjoy life thank you so much